

SIMON McMahon

0490 066 236

simon.nathan.mcmahon@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/simon-mcmahon/

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am an applied mathematics graduate with experience in cloud infrastructure and the statistical/machine learning methods of data science. I am an outside-the-box thinker, problem solver with a deep theoretical understanding.

I believe a crucial difference between myself and other technically talented people in mathematics and data science is my **communication and sales experience**. Throughout my role building a tutoring company part time as I studied in university, I literally explained challenging mathematical concepts 15-20 hours a week for over 3 years. I became well-versed in listening to client feedback, maintaining customer relationships and communicating clearly.

Get in touch and let's have a chat about how I could best help your company.

SKILLS

Programming

(MATLAB, Python, R, SQL, Excel VBA, git)

Problem-solving mindset Research and Data Analysis Data Science

(Tensorflow / Keras / Numpy / Machine Learning).

Explanation of Technical Material
Client acquisition / communication / management

EDUCATION & AWARDS

University of Queensland — Bachelor of Mathematics

2013-2017
Undergraduate degree in Mathematics with a focus on **applied** of

Undergraduate degree in Mathematics with a focus on applied concepts such as statistical methods, operations research, practical optimization, data analysis and financial mathematics.

University of Queensland — Vice Chancellor Scholarship

Awarded a \$12 000 p.a. scholarship based on academic merit. It is the highest value undergraduate scholarship the University of Queensland awards.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jacaranda Finance— Data Analyst

2017 - Present

Developing and deploying a credit scoring algorithm using a variety of statistical and machine learning algorithms to help the staff make better decisions faster. In this role, among other things, have managed large datasets in **SQL**, deployed real time statistical processing as a **web API** using **Microsoft ML server**, tested algorithm accuracy and iterated designs based on client (loan assessor) feedback.

University of Queensland — Casual Academic Tutor

Semester 1, 2017 - Present

Throughout 2017, I was brought on as a tutor for mathematics at the university. This involved presenting and explaining mathematics to a tutorial of 25 people multiple times each week, as well as marking assignments and providing feedback.

Altius Tutoring — Founder and Head Tutor

2013 - 2017

I started a private tutoring company specialising in 1-on-1 tutoring for senior school mathematics, physics and chemistry. Within this role I developed **excellent communication skills** - routinely extracting and dissecting the essence of a complex concept **and explaining it in plain English**. I also gained valuable skills **in sales, marketing** and **scheduling**.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Pro Bono Econos - Volunteer Consultant

Semester 1, 2016

I joined the team in Semester 1 2016 and analysed the economic impact of proposed regional innovations centres in Queensland. I learnt a great deal about assessing client needs in consulting and developed a passion applying mathematics in a real-world environment.

University of Queensland - Student Leader

Semester 1, 2016

University of Queensland - Science Ambassador

March, 2016

Represented the University of Queensland in a public capacity at the World Science fair.

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

SSA (Statistics Society of Australia) & AMSI (Australian Mathematical Sciences Institute)

HOBBIES/INTERESTS

Hiking and bushwalking / Cycling / Board Games / Ultimate Disc

REFEREES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST.